working on your philosophy and all those other things.
Let's go up this ladder
now just to illustrate a point.
Is it possible to multiply your income by 10?
All kids need to hear this.
It's not being taught, I
don't think, in the local schools.
You have to come to a
Jim Rohn seminar to hear this.
I never heard it until I was 25.
It's possible to multiply your income by 10.
If we searched around the Palm Springs area,
could we find somebody that makes $50 an hour?
And the answer is yes, of course.
So it's possible to multiply your income by 10.
Could you multiply it by 10 again?
That's $500 an hour.
If we searched around this area, would we have to search
very long until we find someone that makes $500 an hour?
No. Everybody agrees.
So it's not only possible to multiply.
If you multiply your income by 10,
it's possible to multiply by 10 again.
Now, would it be possible
to multiply it by 10 again?
$5,000 an hour.
What do you suppose I get paid?
It's not open for public disclosure.
I've lectured with, you know, Schwarzkopf and Colin
Powell and Henry Kissinger and all the rest.
They get paid well.
Schwarzkopf gets $65,000 for a one-hour speech.
So all you have to do is become a general in the
Army, win the Gulf War, you get $65,000 for a one-hour speech.
Bill Clinton gets what? $125,000 for a one-hour speech.
And then this just keeps on going.
On up to the stratosphere.
Someone earned $36 million last year for one year's work.
So that's the ladder.
Now, jot this down.
To climb this ladder as high as you wish.
And you've got to underline the word wish.
Because part of your future now is
what you wish and what you want.
How much property will they let you own in America?
As much as you want.
This is wish-want country.
You've dropped into the right place.
As much as you want, as much as you wish.
And not to have any.
Any.
And you live in a country where you can have
as much as you want and as much as you wish.
See, wouldn't that be puzzling
to people outside the country?
As much as you wish.
To climb this ladder as high as you
wish in terms of bringing value to the marketplace.
And becoming valuable to the marketplace.
As high as you wish.
Here's all you have to do.
And Don and Greg heard it all those years ago.
And it's a simple analysis, but it's so true.
Here it is.
One more time.
Learn to work harder on yourself
than you do on your job.
That's the simple philosophy that changed
my life forever starting age 25.
If you work hard on your job,
you can make a living, which is fine.
If you work hard on yourself, you
can make a fortune, which is fine.
can make a fortune, which is super fine.
Everything changed for me when I understood this philosophy.
I didn't mind working hard on my job.
But things didn't seem to change that much.
Then I started working hard on myself to qualify.
So let me put it in a philosophical phrase now.
This is worth the price of whatever
it costs for you to be here today.
Here it is.
Success is something you attract.
By becoming an attractive person.
Success is not something you pursue.
It's something you attract by becoming attractive.
Here's what we teach in leadership.
To attract attractive people, you must be attractive.
And the whole scope of this we call success.
And the whole scope of
this we call now personal development.
You can have more than you've got
because you can become more than you are.
If you can multiply your value by 3, by 5, you
can easily multiply your income by 3, by 5, by 10.
But the key to doing it
is to work hard on yourself.
What is that?
Oh, right.
You can have more than you've got
because you can become more than you are.
Now, that's why I mentioned this
personal development part is learning multiple skills.
If it would serve you, multiple languages.
Okay?
Working hard on yourself.
You know, people are fun to work with.
The key sometimes that's not
fun to work with is yourself.
How come I'm reluctant when I should be excited?
Right?
You just go through this dilemma.
The work we do is fairly easy.
Mr. Shouf, my first mentor, taught me.
You know, the world is mostly full of real nice.
In fact, he said there's only about 11 or
12 real nasty, miserable, horrible people in the whole world.
Now, he said they move around a lot.
So you're bound to find one once in a while.
But if you found one, you say,
hey, there's only 11 more like you.
I can handle that.
I mean, there's not a thousand.
But here's the big challenge.
Working hard on yourself.
Personality and temperament and mindset.
We talked about culture.
All the stuff necessary to individually be responsible,
be a growing, attractive, powerful, skillful, communicating human being.
And the world belongs to you.
Now, to get others to do
the same, that's part of the challenge.
But these multiple skills can help you to do that.
Now, jot down these five key ideas.
That can help us all to
take advantage of the 21st century.
Here's number one.
Work on your personal philosophy.
Your personal philosophy is like a guidance system.
Personal philosophy.
A guidance system.
Now, the subject of philosophy is a lot of work.
But it's not all about that.
The subject of philosophy is a big subject.
You know, spiritual philosophy and economic
philosophy and social and all the rest.
But your personal philosophy now is like a guidance system.
Just draw you an arrow.
That'll be your guidance system.
And your guidance system only does two things.
One, helps you to see the dangers over
here so you don't build on the sand.
Even though at the moment it looks attractive.
Blue sky, fleecy clouds.
Why not build on the sand?
See, you just have to
get smarter and smarter at that.
Not to do that.
Now, your guidance system also helps
you to find the opportunities over here.
And this is what the
drama of life is all about.
Danger riding side by side with opportunity.
Los Angeles.
A place for the most
extraordinary opportunity probably in the world.
Side by side with danger.
In Los Angeles, when the light
turns green, you better not go.
Wait two or three seconds for those
maniacs, right, that are running the red light.
Did you ever blink and say, I can't believe the light
is green and there's cars going this way in front of me?
That's Los Angeles.
If you're a pedestrian and the
light turns green, you better not go.
If it says walk, you better
not walk for a second or two.
To what?
Save your life.
Danger and opportunity.
Side by side.
Learning to understand one so you can avoid it.
How to cash in on the other.
Now, jot this down because
it's got to be taught early.
The guidance system must start early.
When a child goes to school, they've
got to have a good guidance system working.
So they can spot the dangers to their children.
They've got to spot the dangers to their health, the dangers to
their person, the dangers to their thinking, the dangers to their future.
Early, this system has to start.
From early training, ideas, information, parents, teachers.
And the temptation is always there.
When I was a little kid growing up, I saw this cartoon of a little boy
with a little devil on one shoulder and a little angel, right, on the other shoulder.
Both whispering in his ear.
The little devil says, go ahead and do it.
It'll be okay.
A little angel says, no, no, no.
No, no, no.
Won't be okay.
Yes, yes, go ahead.
You can get by with it this time.
No, no, no.
What is that?
It's called high drama.
This is high drama.
Every day of our life, we are tempted.
Cross the line, tempted.
Run the light, tempted.
Sometimes it could be fatal in a moment.
Here's a father who loves his family.
He's a respected citizen of the community.
He's got a thriving business,
but he's late for an appointment.
And he's pushing it in Los Angeles.
And the light turns red and the voice says, go.
You can make it this time.
Besides, you're late.
Go.
And now he's dead.
This is not an evil man.
This is not a bad man.
This is a careless man who in
just a moment of thoughtlessness loses his life.
Loses his life.
So everybody's guidance system has
got to be alert and working.
Whether it's in business, crossing the line.
Whether it's a moral question,
ethical question, all the rest.
All of us.
That's why the great prayer says, lead us around temptation.
Help us to manage this dangerous side.
And then it just goes on and on.
This is part of the great drama.
The spoiler and the creator.
Over here is what?
Evil.
And over here is what?
Good.
Over here is darkness.
Here is light.
Over here is illness.
Over here is what?
Health.
Over here is death.
Over here is what?
Life.
Here is tyranny.
Here is liberty.
Why this drama?
Because it's the only way to create a human drama.
So make this note.
One of the best I have for the day.
Here's what it seems like.
Opposites are in conflict and we are in the middle.
That's the game of life.
Whether it's in business, whether
it's home, social, marriage, personal.
Friendship, health, no matter what it is.
It's the drama.
In your bloodstream there are red corpuscles
to nourish and give life like a mother.
And white corpuscles to fight and kill like a father.
And you gotta have both.
Thank God for white corpuscles that think like a father.
White corpuscles that think negative all day.
White corpuscles say, just show me
some infection and I'll kill it.
Because if I don't kill it, what?
It kills you.
Somebody's gonna get killed today.
White corpuscles say, it's up to
me to make sure it's not you.
So the war is going on.
Friendly bacteria and unfriendly bacteria.
This is the game.
But what if you picked up
a book and the first chapter said,
everything's fine.
Second chapter, everything's fine.
Third chapter, hey, everything is just fine.
Fourth chapter, everything's fine.
Would you finish the book?
And the answer is no.
What kind of a book is this?
That is not the book.
First chapter, the war is on.
Let me read the second chapter and the third chapter.
Isn't this the deal?
Let me give you the last illustration.
Would it be possible to win if you couldn't lose?
And the answer is no.
This is called winning and losing.
What if you put a football under your arm and
we all went with you to the nearest football stadium
and you, with this football under
your arm, crossed the goal line?
Would we cheer and call it a touchdown?
No.
It's not a touchdown until you face the 300 pounders
that want to smash your face in the turf.
And if you can muscle by them and dance
past the secondary and then cross the goal line,
we'd cheer and call it
a touchdown and maybe a championship.
But not without the contest.
So it looks like God started
this whole thing with the angels.
A third of them rebelled and he threw them out.
And that started what we call high drama.
And the high drama continues today
between the spoiler and the creator.
And all we have to do now is figure
out in our business, social, personal, economic, daily life,
how to multiply all life systems together.
How to multiply all life systems by
2, by 3, by 5, by 10,
by following a few simple guidelines.
One is understanding, first of all, philosophy being
like the set of the sail on a sailboat.
The winds are always blowing.
Contrary winds and political winds and social winds.
Familiar winds and unfamiliar winds.
And upside down winds and storms like hit Florida.
So the wind is always blowing.
But to get to your dreams
and the things you want to do,
the things you want for yourself and for
your family and the money and all the rest,
you don't have to curse the wind.
All you have to do is set a better sail.
And that's what sermons are for.
Lyrics from songs.
Dialogue with conversation with friends.
And that's what classes like this are for.
Is to help keep setting better sail.
So that no matter what happens
in 205, 2006, 7, 8, 10,
you will get so good at setting
sail that no matter what winds blow,
it still takes you toward your destination.
That's called the high drama and the game of life.
That's it.
Making sure you're not building on sand.
Making sure your casa grande is built on the rock.
It starts with personal philosophy.
Now to develop personal philosophy,
and only humans have this remarkable ability.
Every life form seems to be
driven by instinct and the genetic code,
except human beings.
In the winter, the goose
flies south because he's a goose.
What else could he do?
But not true human beings.
Human beings go north, south, east, west, all by choice.
Human beings can live one way
for five years, tear up that script,
live another way for the next five years.
You can tear up the old
script and design a new one,
starting at this convention.
And you can change a little
or you can change a lot.
Here's what's extraordinary about human beings.
Let's say that you're here.
Just draw your little star, you're here.
And it looks like if you keep
going like you're going in five years,
you're going to be here.
Just without kidding yourself, you know.
It looks like if I keep
up my present daily activities and all,
it looks like I'm going to be here.
And you're not happy with this five-year destination.
Would it be possible to set
a new five-year destination and say,
I would much rather be up here in five years
than where it looks like I'm
going to be in five years.
Is it possible to make that design,
make these little necessary corrections here,
errors and judgment corrected and all that,
and start going this way and wind
up here in five years instead of here?
Is that possible?
And the answer is yes.
So, you're going to be here.
Is that possible?
And the answer is yes.
And it's all a matter of personal choice.
Right?
You can change a little
or you can change a lot.
You can go with the old
script or with the new script.
Either one.
At age 25, I decided
to tear up the old script.
My mentor said, Mr. Owen, you've been working six years.
How are you doing?
I said, not very well.
He said, I suggest you not do that anymore.
That's a pretty simple analysis.
He said, couldn't we go over the last six years
and find out where your errors and judgment were?
And couldn't we correct those and invest
that correction in the next six years?
I said, I guess we could.
That's what we did.
That's how I went from pennies to fortune.
Incredible.
Only humans can do this.
See, if you were a tree, you'd be stuck.
Right?
If you used up all the nourishment around you,
couldn't move, then you would die.
But that's not true.
So, however little or much you
want to change, that's up to you.
But see, if there's a
class and you don't take it,
and a skill and you don't learn it,
and a discipline and you don't try it,
and if there's a possibility and you don't explore it,
then who are we going to blame?
Nobody but yourself.
This is the land of extraordinary opportunity.
So, jot this down.
Okay, some of you have to leave early.
I've got to leave in about 35 minutes.
To rush away, I wish I didn't have to,
but that's the way it is for today.
Jot this little phrase down,
and it wouldn't hurt to memorize it.
I'll give you time to write it down.
Here it is.
From testimonials and personal experience.
We have enough information.
To conclude that it's possible to
design and live an extraordinary life.
It's possible to design and live an extraordinary life.
Now, I'm going to have
you repeat that back to me.
Let's all say it together.
From testimonials and personal experience.
We have enough information.
To conclude that it's possible to
design and live an extraordinary life.
I'd like to have you remember
that for the rest of your life.
We are surrounded by testimonials.
And all of you wouldn't arrive here
if you didn't have sufficient personal experience.
That we all should keep concluding it's
possible to design and live an extraordinary life.
And whether you do it more slowly than someone else,
or whether you've, you know, set aside the
design for a while and you've been coasting,
this would be a good time today,
during these days of training and teaching,
to get better at the design and living this life.
This extraordinary life.
Now, let me give you the rest of my ideas.
The first one was personal philosophy.
Learning to judge between darkness and light.
Then here's the key, to cooperate with the positive side.
It's like your health.
Just learn to cooperate with the positive side.
But what if the body calls for a
banana and the guy sends it a Budweiser?
Good health calls for a banana.
Now, if you sent the wrong material,
couldn't the body now say,
whose side are you on?
Good health says, I'm working
overtime trying to keep you healthy
and push illness into a strong corner.
I need some cooperation.
And that's what the game of life is all about.
To find out where the dangers are,
minimize those, push them into a small corner.
For a long time in the
world there was more tyranny than liberty.
Now that the walls came down in Germany,
there's now a lot more liberty than tyranny,
along with all of the difficulties and
stresses and terrorism and all the rest.
Nothing new there.
But this is a time of more liberty than tyranny,
more light than darkness,
more health than illness,
more opportunity than danger.
These are extraordinary times.
If there was ever a time to quickly learn,
put it all in order,
and move forward on all life systems
to multiply their values by two, three, five, ten,
this would be the time to do it.
Now here's four more key ideas.
One is personal philosophy.
Here's the next one, attitude.
How we feel plays such
a major part in our future.
First, it's what we know
so we can make wise decisions
about danger and opportunity.
But second is how we feel.
First, it's how you feel about the past.
You need a healthy attitude about the past
so that you use it, not
live in it, but use it.
Not carry it like a burden,
but let the wise lessons
you learned from the past now
serve as fuel to furnish the future.
Next, a good attitude about the future.
You've got to set your goals.
We look back for experience,
but we look forward for inspiration.
We must be instructed and inspired.
No better inspiration than to set your goals.
I started this process when I was 25.
Literally rocked my world, changed my life.
I had no idea it was so simple.
Here's how simple it is.
Decide what you want, write it all down.
Make a list of the people you want to meet.
Make a list of the books you want to read.
Make a list of the classes you want to take.
Make a list of the skills you want to learn.
Make a list of the cities you want to visit.
Make a list of the investments you want to have.
Just make these lists.
Here's the next key now.
Start checking them off.
Put a lot of little things on some list
so you can start checking off something right away.
That's part of the fun.
Here's what's next.
If you check off something major, celebrate.
Because that inspires you to
make a longer list of goals.
And put everything on your list.
Little things, insignificant to
someone else, important to you.
I put a little revenge on my first list.
My mentor said it was healthy.
Some of the people who said I couldn't succeed,
kid from the farms of
Idaho, they went on my list.
Couldn't wait to get my new
car. Drive it up on their lawn.
Say, oh, pardon me, here's
the money to have it fixed.
Just little satisfactions.
My Japanese friend, Toro Ikeda, San Jose, California,
put on his first list, a Caucasian gardener.
Yeah, I like that, Toro.
Way back then, everybody had a Japanese gardener.
Everybody, Japanese gardener.
He said, I'm Japanese, I'm
going to have a Caucasian gardener.
Okay, little satisfactions, right?
Set your goals.
Decide what you want.
Write it down.
Start checking them off.
It's powerful stuff.
Next, it's how you feel about everybody.
If you want to be a leader, a true leader,
entrepreneur of the highest order,
well respected, unique in your field,
here's number one, how you feel about everybody.
And this is philosophical as well.
You cannot succeed by yourself.
So a unique sense of appreciation of everybody
goes with the territory of leadership.
It takes everybody for each of us to be successful.
One person doesn't make an economy.
One person doesn't make a symphony orchestra.
It takes everybody.
For this gathering today,
all of you had to
be here to make this gathering.
Everybody.
If one of you were missing,
there wouldn't be this many people here.
Everybody to make something work for the office, whatever.
The enterprise takes everybody.
The gift of America is everybody who
came over the last two, three hundred years,
bringing with them their gifts.
No country has become such a
depository of the gifts of the world
like America has over the last two, three hundred years.
People coming, bringing their gifts.
Gift of language, gift of learning,
gift of politics, gift of government,
gift of medicine, gift of healing,
gift of music,
gift of the work ethic.
All this came in steady
streams from all over the world,
making us unusual because of the gifts that were brought.
And to understand that and appreciate it,
is to be able to do it.
To understand that and appreciate it,
now gives you open access to the
market that's available to make your fortune.
Now what I love to do is
go back where these gifts came from.
Not long ago I was in Rome.
I had a thousand people in my class.
Someone suggested,
Jim Rohn loves the music of Andrea Bocelli,
the blind opera singer from Italy.
So when they introduced me,
I walked to the podium and all
one thousand of these Italians stood up
and sang for me one of Andrea Bocelli's songs.
In true Italian style.
Tears.
I described it to my grandchildren later.
I said, here was the scene.
A choir of a thousand and an audience of one.
And that was me.
I thought, here's where some of these gifts came from.
The gift of poetry.
The gifts.
So learn to appreciate the gifts.
Now the last attitude is how you feel about yourself.
Nothing more powerful than self-esteem,
which creates self-confidence.
The greatest steps towards
success come from self-confidence.
And that comes from self-esteem.
Doing what you know you should,
so that at the end of the day,
you have high, high self-esteem.
That's attitude.
Now here's the third of the five ideas.
One was personal philosophy.
Second was attitude.
Number three, activity.
The activity now is the work part, the labor part.
The old formula says six days
of labor, one day of rest.
Don't rest too long.
The weeds take the garden.
But here's what else to remember
about the six days of labor.
They are miracle working days.
That's how you turn nothing into something.
You cannot speak it.
You cannot speak it into something.
You know, some are trying affirmations, but that's silly.
I do believe in affirmations as
long as you affirm the truth.
The truth.
If you're broke, best thing to affirm is,
I am broke.
You put that up on the refrigerator.
It's called life changing.
If that doesn't do it, put this up there.
I live in America and I'm broke.
Something is wrong.
I've been to college and I'm broke.
See that, if you affirm the
truth now, those affirmations are good.
Because it's the truth that sets you free.
Someone says, every day in every
way I'm getting better and better.
What if that's not true?
Make this note.
Affirmation without discipline is the beginning of delusion.
It's not called six days of affirmation.
It's called six days of what?
Work.
Labor.
But why embrace the work?
Why embrace the work?
It is because the work builds the city.
The work conquers disease.
The work builds an office.
The work builds a career.
The working on good health builds good health.
It's the work that builds a relationship.
The miracle piece of turning
nothing into something is the work.
So embrace and look forward to
the work that changes nothing into something.
Ideas and faith into reality.
Wisdom and faith, uninvested in activity, serves no purpose.
But wisdom and faith invested in action, activity, creates cities, creates careers,
creates fortunes, creates all good and marvelous things that humans can enjoy.
The activity, the work.
Embrace the work.
I must come here to be of some
value to all of you and do the work.
The work of language.
The work of words.
Ideas put in phrases that can be
understood, maybe create some enlightenment from it.
So I must come and do the work.
But if I do the work, some new stories
may come spinning out of this session here today.
I hope so.
So six days, have you got that now?
Six days work, one day rest.
Don't rest too long, the weeds take the garden.
Don't get these numbers mixed up now.
Six and one.
Okay.
Now here's the last two.
The next one is measure progress.
Because if you're gonna play the great drama game of life,
the key is to keep measuring progress to see how you're doing.
How's your health doing?
How's your income doing?
How are your investments doing?
If you're building a house, how is it coming along?
What's going on?
Measuring progress.
That's what we call the name of the game.
Here's how we teach it to our children.
You must make measurable progress in reasonable time.
That's about as simple as you
can put it to the kids.
You're required to make
measurable progress in reasonable time.
Now we must be reasonable with time.
You can't say to someone every
five minutes, how are you doing now?
Five minutes later, how are you doing now?
This guy says, I haven't left
the building yet, give me a break.
So five minutes to ask for a
count or a measure is too soon.
Five years is too long, too
late, too many things can go wrong.
So reasonable time.
Here's reasonable time.
One, at the end of the day.
Don't let more than a day go
by with what you check and measure something.
Count, measure, take a look at.
My mama taught good health.
I've been healthy all my life.
My papa lived to be 93, never did retire.
When he died, his paycheck was waiting for him.
Mama was good.
Mama said, an apple a day.
Not once in a while, apple a day.
I've modified it a little, apple juice, apple pie.
Mama said, apple a day.
So at the end of the day, check off.
The old prophet said, if you're angry, try
to solve it before the sun goes down.
Don't carry it over for another day.
Tomorrow it might be too heavy to carry.
A conversation a father should have with
his daughter today because the magic is there.
If you wait until tomorrow, the magic could be gone.
So, that's the day.
Today, a reasonable time to count.
How are you doing?
You have how many properties now?
Right?
It's been six months.
You have how many now?
It's been one year.
Now you have how many?
It's been two years and now you have how many?
How many?
It's the key.
Count, count.
It's the deal.
Success is a numbers game.
How many years do you want
your child to spend in fourth grade?
Approximately.
About what?
One.
One grade, one year.
Progress, one grade, one year.
And you've got to set up your own measuring system.
Don't wait for somebody else to do it.
You set it up.
Because society doesn't require you not have a heart attack.
That you must require of yourself.
Society doesn't demand that you build
a financial wall around your family.
Nothing can get through.
That you must demand of yourself.
So, the government's not there to measure.
Society's not there to measure.
You must be responsible enough to measure yourself.
How are you coming on
this financial wall around your family?
Nothing can get through.
Get through.
How are you doing?
And whether it's a few pounds to lose, or whether it's
a financial wall, or whether it's a growing office, whatever it is.
Find some ways to measure so you don't become disillusioned.
Thinking, oh, it looks okay when it really isn't okay.
Measure, check.
It's the game to play.
Now, here's number five.
First was personal philosophy.
We're affected by what we know.
Second is attitude.
We're affected by how we feel.
I've had this debate with Zig now for 45 years.
Should you start with education or motivation?
The attitude's the motivation.
Philosophy is the education.
Zig says motivation first, then education.
I say education first, then motivation.
It's a good debate.
I say, Zig, if a
guy's an idiot, you motivate him.
Now you've got a motivated idiot.
So score one for me.
But now Zig comes back.
Here's what Zig says.
Yes, but you have to be motivated to be educated.
I say, what?
That's very good.
So our debate continues.
But you need both.
Philosophy, guidance system, set sail so that no matter
how the wind blows in the next few years,
you'll be okay because you've learned to set sail,
adjust, learn, study, grow, take notes like you're doing today.
The hard work of learning is just as hard for you
to learn and study today as it is for me to lecture.
Both of it's hard work.
But it's the work that pays extraordinarily well.
Okay.
Then number three was activity.
This is the miracle piece.
The six-sevenths of your life.
Six-sevenths.
Engaged in activity that creates career, creates a relationship, creates a
city, builds the future, creates wealth, power, influence, all the rest.
Activity.
Then measuring progress.
Don't kid yourself.
Don't be deluded into thinking things looks okay.
You know, the bank's full of money.
That may not be the only sign to check.
Okay.
The old prophet said, the vineyard looks good,
but make sure you check for the little foxes.
The little foxes that can't be seen, that are eating
on the vines, eating on the vines, spoiling the vines.
The little foxes.
So that you don't build on sand, build
on rock, save the day in the future.
Now here's the last one.
And it's called lifestyle.
Because the essence of life is
not a Ferrari or a bank account.
Okay.
It's not a million dollars.
Here's the essence of life.
Learning to live a good life.
To design and live an extraordinary life.
Let me give you my short list
of what I think comprises a good life.
Learning to live a good life.
Number one, productivity.
And it doesn't matter if you're
a person of modest means or wealthy.
Productivity is the name of the game.
name of the game you must that's what biggest
share of our life is to produce to produce the
old prophet said the sleep of a laboring man is
sweet the sleep of a working person is sweet a
producer producer not a drifter not the sleep of a
goof-off man no not the sleep of a joker no the
sleep of a producer is sweet second friendship
friendships that endure Don great we go back
what twenty-seven years ago we go back twenty-seven years
ago we go back twenty-seven years ago we go
back twenty-seven twenty-eight years long time good friends
friends are those wonderful people who know all
about you and still like you right those
those are good friends next now is
your heritage keep that alive because that's
what makes America great the gifts that
came from all over the world still in
service still in display the costumes and
the customs and the the language and
the poetry and the literature all that made
America great that came from all over the world
deposit it here keep that alive and
growing language music customs Fiesta's all the good
things that come from your culture your
heritage New Cape America lively unique is
nothing like it in the history of the world
six thousand years of his makes a strong Matt
us powerful makes us the envy
of the world next is your spirituality
whatever you might believe about spirituality
i've got three words for you to consider
jot these down remember them forever number one study
whatever your spiritual persuasion study
it don't leave it unstudied
don't leave your spiritual heritage
unstudied so study number two practice
don't leave your spirituality on practiced whether
it's one-on-one in the marketplace or synagogue
or church whatever studied number
one practiced number two three taught
don't leave your spirituality
untaught. Pass along what's become valuable and beneficial
to you. Pass it along to someone else,
especially to your children. That's how we
build a strong foundation for the country.
Families well taught, well instructed.
Next, something my parents taught me
that they practiced all their life.
Now I practice. Don't miss anything. Don't
miss the game. Don't miss the concert. Don't
miss the performance. Don't miss the show.
Don't miss the conversation. Don't miss the sermon.
Don't miss the class. Don't miss
anything. Go, look, see, learn, try, taste.
Let that flavor of life be part of you.
Let that flavor of life be part of your lifestyle.
When my father was 73 years old, after my
mother was gone, when my father was 73 years old,
or 93 years old, before he died, if you would
have called him at 10, 30, 11 o'clock at night,
he wouldn't be home. He's at the concert. He's
at church. He's at the rodeo. He's watching the
kids play softball every night somewhere.
My parents taught it, practiced it. Unbelievable.
Don't miss anything. Don't miss the
taste, the language. Elton John sings,
she lived her life like a candle in the wind,
never knowing who to cling to when the rain set in.
What if you missed that? See, that wouldn't be good.
George Harrison used to sing before he died, if
not for you, the winter would hold no spring.
Couldn't hear a robin sing.
I just wouldn't have a clue.
If not for you. Wow.
Go taste, go listen, go enjoy.
Now jot this down. There's a genius
within all of us that recognizes extraordinary value.
Besides Greg and Don and, you know, Tony
and a whole long list of others, Mark Hughes,
some of my claims to fame, a
name maybe you might recognize, Ann Geddes.
Does that name ring a bell? Especially for
the women? She takes photos of these little babies
in different settings, right? That's Ann Geddes.
She started attending my seminars like this in
Australia 26, 25, 26 years ago. And she says
Jim Rohn seminars changed my life. She's been to the
two-day weekend seminar and all the rest. I got to
know Ann and her husband. Now she's a member of the
New York New York Association. She's really
famous and rich. We were celebrating her extraordinary
visit to New York with a friend of mine. We
were in New Zealand. And Ann and her husband and Terry
Butler, a friend of mine in Australia, and myself,
the four of us, were celebrating Ann's New York success.
And Terry found a bottle of Chateau Ikem.
One of the finest wines in the world. I
know he paid about $600 for it, which was
New Zealand dollars, probably about $400 maybe,
American money. But anyway, nice bottle of wine, $400.
For the four of us to share.
Now, we probably,
and I'm sure we did hope
that no one we knew came by.
It's just one of those things, right?
Because there's only four and there's only one bottle. But anyway, if you
would have come by, I'm sure we would have let you taste this wine.
And if you would have tasted this wine,
here's what I'm sure you would have said.
I'll bet this wine is going to be a success.
This wine costs $400 a bottle.
That's what you would have said.
Something called the genius within would have recognized
something extraordinary, even though you're not a wine connoisseur.
Something would have told you.
That's what poetry is all about.
Somebody that puts the words together
and you say, wow, that is extraordinary.
That is fine.
Music.
Language.
Conversation.
Learning to recognize the extraordinary and the fine.
So I'm asking you to do that.
Go see, go look, go taste, go enjoy.
Now, one last thought.
And my time of departure has finally
arrived and I have to slip away.
I wish I could stay and visit the rest
of the day, but I do have to go.
Here's the last part.
God says, now I'm an amateur
on God, but here's my best shot.
God says, if you will plant
the seed, I will make the tree.
Probably one of the best arrangements ever.
What if you had to make the tree?
See, that'd keep you up late night trying
to figure out how do you make a tree.
God says, no, don't worry about that.
I got the tree stuff down.
But I've always wanted to do that.
I've always wanted to do that.
I didn't want to be alone.
That's why I created all those
angels, even though the big drama occurred.
I still like to work, right, with
humans that are interested in working together.
So let's work together.
And I think that's the deal.
God says, you plant the
seed, I will make the tree.
So here's my last bit of language.
And it says, we have a chance
to participate in the working of miracles.
We have a chance to
participate in the working of miracles.
Part of it is the work of our hands.
Part of it is the work of our language.
Part of it is the
work of a soul that cares.
Part of it is the work of a compassionate heart.
Doing extraordinary work that affects other people's lives.
In building enterprise,
fortunes, future, communities, church.
We do good work.
So, God bless America in our journey into the future.
As we do our work to contribute to society.
And hopefully it will all help us to do incredible things
as a country to compete among the nations of the world.
So that America can continue to
bless the rest of the world.
But thanks to Greg and Don one
more time for inviting me for a chance.
Thank you.
Next time I see you, my therapy will be complete.
And I will be back to 100% physically.
And until then, God bless.
See you next time.
Thank you.